




	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LINQ on K-State CIS 400 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/05-linq/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in LINQ on K-State CIS 400 Textbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/05-linq/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/05-linq/01-introduction/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/05-linq/01-introduction/index.html</guid>
      <description>We saw in the last chapter how many web applications are built around the concept of resources. An online store has products to sell. A social media application has people with accounts. Resource-oriented web applications therefore need to store these resources in some fashion - possibly as objects in some kind of collection, or possibly with a database.
Key Terms Some key terms to learn in this chapter are:
Database Relational Database Object-Oriented Database Document-Based Database Structured Query Language (SQL) Language Integrated Query (LINQ) Anonymous Types Extension Methods Key Skills The key skills to develop in this chapter are:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Databases</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/05-linq/02-databases/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/05-linq/02-databases/index.html</guid>
      <description>We use the term &amp;ldquo;Database&amp;rdquo; to describe a program primarily designed to efficiently store and retrieve data. These are often used in conjunction with other kinds of applications - such as web applications or desktop applications. Why use a separate program rather than building this storage and retrieval into the application we are building? There are a lot of possible reasons, but some common ones are:
Centralized access. Consider a desktop application that tracks inventory for a large company.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LINQ</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/05-linq/03-linq/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/05-linq/03-linq/index.html</guid>
      <description>One solution that Microsoft has developed to tackle the disconnect between relational databases and C# is Language Integrated Query (LINQ). This technology integrates querying directly into the C# language. It can act as a bridge to a MS SQL server, replacing the need for writing SQL queries and processing the results. But it can also be used to query collections that implement the IEnumerable interface, as well as XML files. As such, we can design the logic of our program to use LINQ, and change out the data source for any of these options with minimal refactoring.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LINQ Syntax</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/05-linq/04-linq-syntax/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/05-linq/04-linq-syntax/index.html</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s discuss some of the more common operations we might want to perform with LINQ. Please note that this is not an exhaustive list - just some of the most common operations you will be encountering at this time.
Data Source For these examples, we&amp;rsquo;ll be using a data source consisting of Student objects. These are defined by the class:
public class Student { public string EID; public string First; public string Last; public double GPA; public int Age; public string Major; }And the variable students is a List&amp;lt;Student&amp;gt; that we can assume is populated with initialized student objects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extension Methods</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/05-linq/05-extension-methods/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/05-linq/05-extension-methods/index.html</guid>
      <description>In order to use LINQ with your IEnumerable collections, you must include this using statement:
using System.LINQ Without it, the LINQ collection methods will not be available. You might be wondering why, as your collections are mostly defined in the System.Collections or System.Collections.Generic namespaces.
The answer is that LINQ on collections is implemented using extension methods . This is a C# feature that allows you to add methods to any class, even a sealed class.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/05-linq/06-summary/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/05-linq/06-summary/index.html</guid>
      <description>In this chapter we learned about LINQ, Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s query technology for querying collections, relational databases, and XML files (along with community implementations for many other queryable things). We saw how to use both query and method syntax provided by LINQ to perform common query operations. Finally, we examined the mechanism LINQ uses to provide new functionality to IEnumerable collections - extension methods. We even implemented a few extension methods of our own!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>