




	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Core Web Technologies on K-State CIS 400 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/01-core-web-technologies/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Core Web Technologies on K-State CIS 400 Textbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/01-core-web-technologies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/01-core-web-technologies/01-introduction/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/01-core-web-technologies/01-introduction/index.html</guid>
      <description>The World-Wide-Web is a tool that you likely use every day - and it&amp;rsquo;s being used to deliver you this textbook. There are several core technologies that enable the web to work, and these are the focus of this chapter.
Key Terms Some key terms to learn in this chapter are:
World-Wide-Web Hyper-Text Markup Language (HTML) Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) JavaScript (JS) Hyper-Text Transfer Protocol (HTTP) </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Core Web Technologies</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/01-core-web-technologies/02-core-web-technologies/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:05 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/01-core-web-technologies/02-core-web-technologies/index.html</guid>
      <description>The World-Wide Web was the brainchild of Sir Tim Berners-Lee . It was conceived as a way to share information across the Internet; in Sir Berners-Lee&amp;rsquo;s own words describing the idea as he first conceived it:
This project is experimental and of course comes without any warranty whatsoever. However, it could start a revolution in information access.
Clearly that revolution has come to pass. The web has become part of our daily lives.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hyper-Text Markup Language</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/01-core-web-technologies/03-html/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/01-core-web-technologies/03-html/index.html</guid>
      <description>Hyper-Text Markup Language (HTML), is one of the three core technologies of the world-wide-web, along with Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) and Javascript (JS). Each of these technologies has a specific role to play in delivering a website. HTML defines the structure and contents of the web page. It is a markup language, similar to XML and the XAML you have been working with (indeed, HTML is based on the SGML (Standardized General Markup Language) standard, which XML is also based on, and XAML is an extension of XML).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cascading Style Sheets</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/01-core-web-technologies/04-css/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/01-core-web-technologies/04-css/index.html</guid>
      <description>Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) is the second core web technology of the web. It defines the appearance of web pages by applying stylistic rules to matching HTML elements. CSS is normally declared in a file with the .css extension, separate from the HTML files it is modifying, though it can also be declared within the page using the &amp;lt;style&amp;gt; element, or directly on an element using the style attribute.
CSS Rules A CSS rule consists of a selector and a definition block, i.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/01-core-web-technologies/05-js/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/01-core-web-technologies/05-js/index.html</guid>
      <description>Javascript (or ECMAScript, which is the standard Javascript is derived from), was originally developed for Netscape Navigator by Brendon Eich . The original version was completed in just 10 days. The name &amp;ldquo;javascript&amp;rdquo; was a marketing move by Netscape as they had just secured the rights to use Java Applets in their browser, and wanted to tie the two languages together. Similarly, they pushed for a Java-like syntax, which Brandon accommodated.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hyper-Text Transfer Protocol</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/01-core-web-technologies/06-http/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/01-core-web-technologies/06-http/index.html</guid>
      <description>At the heart of the world wide web is the Hyper-Text Transfer Protocol (HTTP). This is a protocol defining how HTTP servers (which host web pages) interact with HTTP clients (which display web pages).
It starts with a request initiated from the web browser (the client). This request is sent over the Internet using the TCP protocol to a web server. Once the web server receives the request, it must decide the appropriate response - ideally sending the requested resource back to the browser to be displayed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/01-core-web-technologies/07-summary/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/01-core-web-technologies/07-summary/index.html</guid>
      <description>In this chapter we explored the three client-side core web technologies: HTML, which defines the content of a web page; CSS, which defines the appearance of the web page; and Javascript, which adds interactivity to the web page. We also examined Hyper-Text Transfer Protocol (HTTP) which is used to transmit web pages from the server to the client. We learned that HTTP always follows a request-response pattern, and how both requests and responses are simply streams of data that follow a specific layout.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>