




	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deployment on K-State CIS 400 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/06-deployment/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Deployment on K-State CIS 400 Textbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/06-deployment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/06-deployment/01-introduction/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/06-deployment/01-introduction/index.html</guid>
      <description>Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve explored building web applications and writing web servers, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore in more detail how to make them available on the web, a process known as deployment.
Key Terms Some key terms to learn in this chapter are:
Deployment IP Address IPV4 IPV6 Domain Name Ports Virtual Machine Key Skills The key skills to develop in this chapter are:
Setting up your web applications to deploy to a virtual machine </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web Addresses</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/06-deployment/02-web-addresses/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/06-deployment/02-web-addresses/index.html</guid>
      <description>IP Addresses As we discussed previously, when we visit web pages in our browser, the browser makes a HTTP or HTTPS request against the web server for the resource. For this request to be sent to the right server, we must first determine the server&amp;rsquo;s address. This address takes the form of an Internet Protocol (IP) address. There are currently two ways these IP addresses are specified, IPv4 and IPv6. An IPv4 address consists of 32 bits split into 8 bit chunks, and is typically expressed as four integers between 0 and 255 separated by periods.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secure HTTP</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/06-deployment/03-secure-http/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/06-deployment/03-secure-http/index.html</guid>
      <description>We have talked several times about HTTP and HTTPS, without really discussing what is different about these two approaches other than HTTPS is &amp;ldquo;secure&amp;rdquo;. Essentially, HTTPS uses the same protocol as HTTP, but requests and responses are encrypted rather than being sent as plain text. This encryption is handled at a level below HTTP, in the communication layer (currently this uses TLS - Transport Layer Security ). This encryption is done through symmetric crypography using a shared secret.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web Hosting</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/06-deployment/04-web-hosting/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/06-deployment/04-web-hosting/index.html</guid>
      <description>To host your website, you will need:
A computer connected to the Internet A web server program listening at port 80 and/or 433 (depending on if you are using secure communications) If you are using secure communications, a security certificate issued by a valid authority. Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt offers free certificates, and is a good source for starting web developers A domain name (while this is technically optional, if you expect users to visit your website you&amp;rsquo;ll probably need one) While you have been running your website in debug mode on your development computer, you probably won&amp;rsquo;t use it to host your actual website on the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Machines</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/06-deployment/05-virtual-machines/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/06-deployment/05-virtual-machines/index.html</guid>
      <description>A virtual machine is a simulated computing device. Let&amp;rsquo;s start with a simple example. You can play classic NES and Super NES games using the Switch . How is this done? Does the Switch contain the same hardware as the original NES or SNES? No. It uses a NVIDA Tegra processor, which utilizes the 64-bit ARM architecture. The NES used an 8-bit CPU, and the SNES used a 16-bit CPU. These are very different architectures.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/06-deployment/06-summary/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cis400/3-web-development/06-deployment/06-summary/index.html</guid>
      <description>In this chapter we discussed what is necessary for hosting a web application: a computer running your web server, a static Internet Protocol address, a domain name that maps to your IP addresss, and a security certificate for using HTTPS. Each of these concepts we explored in some detail. We saw how using HTTPS allows encrypted end-to-end communication between the web client and server, as well as providing assurance that the server we are communicating with is the one we intended to make requests from.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>